Finding Aid of the Woman's Club of Wisconsin Records, 1870-2012
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1870-2012, UWM Manuscript Collection 221; 27.3 cubic ft. (32 boxes) 2 oversize folders
  - 4. Woman's Club of Wisconsin, 1870-2012
    - Committees
      - Program
        - Minutes, 1927-1928, 1980-1988 (Box 12, Folder 22)
        - Minutes, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 7)
        - Minutes, 2001-2004 (Box 32, Folder 19)
        - Monday
          - Committee Description and Members, 1941-1979 (Box 12, Folder 23)
          - Correspondence, 1954-1971 (Box 12, Folder 24)
          - Minutes, 1955-1978 (Box 12, Folder 25)
          - Program Schedules, 1965-1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
          - Programs, 1950s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 27-30)
          - Reports, 1940-1969 (Box 12, Folder 31-32)
        - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1900, 1942-1985 (Box 12, Folder 33)
        - Photo Album, Club Events, 1987 (Box 14, Volume 27)
        - Photo Album, Special Events, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Volume 28)
        - Photographs, Miscellaneous Events, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - Program Schedules, 1954-1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Program Schedules, 1979-1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Programs, 1870-1890 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
        - Programs, 1890-1968 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
        - Programs, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - Programs, 1980s, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
        - Reports, 2001-2004 (Box 32, Folder 20)
        - Reports and Budget, 1970-1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
        - Scrapbooks, Programs and Publicity, 1948-1951 (Box 14, Volume 29-32)
        - Thursday
          - Committee Members, 1936-1977 (Box 13, Folder 12)
          - Committee Policies, 1947-1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
          - Correspondence, 1958, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 14)
          - Minutes, 1927-1968, 1974-1978 (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
          - Program Calendars, 1952-1977 (Box 13, Folder 17)
          - Program Reports, 1970-1985 (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
          - Programs, 1955-1979 (Box 13, Folder 20-23)
        - Tours
          - Calendars and Events, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 24)
          - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 8)
          - House Tour, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
          - Lyric Opera (Chicago), 1981-1986 (Box 13, Folder 25)
          - Program Tours, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Public Relations
        - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 11)
        - Publicity Chairs, 1955-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Research and Long Term Planning
        - Committee Members and Policies, 1958-1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence, 1966-1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 24, Folder 12)
        - Evaluation Report, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 13)
        - Minutes, 1958-1986 (Box 15, Folder 4-7)
        - Minutes, 1990-1995 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Planning Literature, 1974-1995 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Plans and Reports, 1976-1995 (Box 15, Folder 10)
        - Strategic Plans for 1991-1995, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 11)
        - Strategic Plans for 1993-1997, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Science
        - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 15, Folder 13)
        - Flower Sketches, 1892 (Box 15, Volume 33)
    - Legal Documents
      - Articles of Incorporation, Association and Historical Landmark Status, 1910, 1921, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Building Improvements, 1929, 1933, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Court Cases Involving WCW, 1928, 1936, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Insurance Titles, 1961-1965, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - IRS Case on Code Change, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Last Will and Testaments that Pertain to WCW, 1908, 1959, 1979, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Parking Lot Deeds and Titles, 1961-1965 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Parking Lot History and Background, 1961-1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Parking Lot Leases, 1970-1984 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Real Estate Title, 1872 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Tax Status Information, 1920-1931, 1964-1991 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Meetings
      - Annual
        - 2002-2004 (Box 31, Folder 4-6)
        - Agendas, 1973-1998 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Board Reports
          - Corresponding Secretary, 1887, 1924, 1949-1955, 1974-1991 (Box 17, Folder 5)
          - Recording Secretary, 1953-1954, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 6)
          - Vice President (1st)/Personnel Chair, 1974-1991 (Box 17, Folder 7)
          - Vice President (2nd)/Membership Chair, 1971-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - Committee Reports, A-Z, 1953-1994 (Box 17, Folder 9-36)
        - Meeting Announcements, 1958-2000 (Box 17, Folder 37)
        - Minutes, 1924-1936, 1953, 1960-1989 (Box 17, Folder 2-4)
        - Past President's Day, 1963-1995 (Box 17, Folder 38)
        - Photographs, 1963, 1997-1998, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - President's Report, 1953, 1995-1998 (Box 17, Folder 38)
        - Rules of Order, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
        - Sample Ballots, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Club, 1883-1923 (Box 17, Volume 34-45)
      - Election, Minutes, 1984-1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Quarterly, Agendas, 1960-1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Quarterly, Minutes, 1923-1982 (Box 18, Folder 3-11)
      - Quarterly/Weekly, Minutes, 1947-1952 (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
      - Weekly, Minutes, 1923-1967 (Box 18, Folder 14-21)
    - Newsletters, 1951-1959 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Newsletters, 1964-1982 (Box 18, Folder 22-30)
    - Newsletters, 1983-1988 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Newsletters, 1991-2000 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Newsletters, 2001-2005 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Newsletters, Volunteer Voice, 2000-2001 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Newsletters, Volunteer Voice, 2002-2004 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Photographs
      - Christmas, 1980-1987, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 5-11)
      - Committees, 2001-2003 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Events
        - Book Sale, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Club Style Show, 2001-2006 (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - External Events, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 15)
        - Goodwill Style Show, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Gourmet Dinners, 1990-2005 (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - Halloween Hat Party, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 18)
        - Holiday Ball, 1999-2001 (Box 25, Folder 19)
        - Lecture Luncheons, 2002-2004 (Box 25, Folder 20)
        - Miscellaneous Club Events, 1980-2003, undated (Box 25, Folder 21-22)
        - Spa Day, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 23)
        - A Taste of India, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 24)
        - Theatre, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 25)
        - The Twelve Centuries of Christmas Program, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 26)
        - Zita Style Show, 1986-1999 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - Foundation Day Event, 1992-1999, 2004-2005 (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - History, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - House
        - Early Interior, undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
        - Food, undated (Box 25, Folder 31)
        - Interior Album, 1986, undated (Box 25, Folder 32)
        - Interior/Exterior, 1991-2002, undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
        - Men's Lounge Americana, Before and After, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - Repairing Cupola, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Contact Sheets, undated (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - Negatives, undated, 35 mm safety film negatives (Box 30)
      - Photo Album, 1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - Photo Album, Miscellaneous Events, 1959, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Photo Album, Miscellaneous Events, 1961, 1973, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - President Portraits, 1884-1918, 1981-2009 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - President Portraits and Golden Anniversary Scrapbook, 1876-1979 (Box 29)
      - Singers, 2001-2003 (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Staff, 1985, 2001, undated (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Yearbooks, 1884-1915 (Box 19, Volume 46-47)
    - Yearbooks, 1885-1954 (Box 19, Folder 4-12)
    - Yearbooks, 1954-2003 (Box 24, Folder 18-27)
  - 5. Woman's Club of Wisconsin Foundation, Inc., 1961-2004
    The Woman's Club of Wisconsin Foundation, Inc. was founded to assume many of the duties previously handled by the welfare committee. The foundation is solely a philanthropic organization, in charge of reviewing and awarding grant money to various community organizations in need of assistance. Although legally a separate entity, the foundation works closely with the Woman's Club and shares many club projects. Records include board of directors and committee minutes, financial reports, and publicity materials.
    - Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1964-1994 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Benefits, 1991-1993 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors Minutes, 1965-1994 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Community Outreach and Foundation Development Committees, 1988-1994 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Community Outreach Committee, 1992-1999 (Box 20, Folder 5-8)
    - Community Outreach Committee Minutes, 2001-2004 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Community Outreach Committee Reports, 2001-2004 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Drought, Bette, Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Financial Policies, 1982-1990 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Financial Reports, 1961-1963, 1970-1990 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
    - Financial Statements, 1990-1994 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Foundation Committee Minutes, 2001-2004 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Foundation Committee Reports, 2002-2004 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Foundation Day, Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Foundation Development Committee, 1991-1996 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Foundation Tea and Toy Show, 1991-1996 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Grant Allocation Committee
      - Annual Reports, 1967-2001 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Grant Applications, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Grant Letters, 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Job Description, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Meetings, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Minutes, 1992-2001 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Minutes, 2001-2002 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Notices, 1991-1999 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Grant Allocation Newsletter, Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Grant Recipients, 1991-2002 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Grants, 1967-1994 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Job Descriptions, 1993, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Policies and Guidelines, 1989-1993 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Publicity, 1991-1994 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Wiley, Barbara, Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 29)
- Additions, 1980-2001, Accession 2010-059; 1.4 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Additions of records from 1999 to 2001, as well as miscellaneous records from earlier years (1980-2000).
- Athenaeum Board Meeting Minutes, 1893-1919, Accession 2012-045; .2 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of 3 volumes of Athenaeum board meeting minutes, dating from 1893 to 1907 and 1913 to 1919.